A Guide to the State Historical Records Advisory Board files of the Virginia State Archivist at the Library of Virginia, 1996-2007
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
State Historical Records Advisory Board files of the Virginia State Archivist at the Library of Virginia,, 1996-2007
The Library of Virginia
44456
3 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the State Archivist, Library of Virginia, 31 August 2009.
Biographical Information
The State Historical Records Advisory Board serves as the central advisory body for historical records planning and related projects developed and carried out by the State. The Board may publish and sponsor surveys of conditions and needs of historical records in the State; review records and proposals by institutions in the State and make recommendations to the National Historical Publications and Records Commission.
Scope and Content
These correspondence and subject files relate to the State Archivist's involvement with the State Historical Records Advisory Board (SHRAB). The material documents various projects and grants undertaken by the Board and various local government entities and other institutions around Virginia. Also includes files related to NHPRC grant applications and evaluations; and meeting minutes and related attachments.
Contents List
- Board correspondence, 1996-2003 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 1997 Jan (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 1997 Feb 13 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 1998 June 26 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 1999 Oct 29 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 2000 June 23 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, 2000 Oct 27 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Abingdon, VA, 2001 June 8 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Abingdon, VA, 2001 June 8 (Box 2)
- Board meeting, Abingdon, VA, 2001 June 8 (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Winchester, VA, 2001 Oct (Box 2)
- Board meeting, Winchester, VA, 2001 Oct (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Newport News, VA, 2002 June 21 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Newport News, VA, 2002 June 21 (Box 2)
- Board meeting, Newport News, VA, 2002 June 21 (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Winchester, VA, 2002 Oct 12 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Lynchburg, VA, 2002 Nov 15 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Lynchburg, VA, 2002 Nov (Box 3)
- Board meeting, 2003 Mar 28 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Staunton, VA, 2003 Oct 24 (Box 1)
- Board meeting, Staunton, VA, 2003 Oct 24 (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Accomac, VA, 2004 May (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Fredericksburg, VA, 2004 Oct (Box 2)
- Board meeting, Fredericksburg, VA, 2004 Oct (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Williamsburg, VA, 2005 May (Box 3)
- Board meeting, 2005 Oct (Box 3)
- Board meeting, 2006 June (Box 3)
- Board meeting, 2006 Oct (Box 3)
- Board meeting, Richmond, VA, 2007 Nov (Box 2)
- Board meeting, Richmond, VA, 2007 Nov (Box 3)
- Board member evaluations, 2001 (Box 2)
- Charts, n.d. (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 2007 (Box 3)
- COSHRC, 1998 Jan (Box 1)
- Current Board member lists, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
- Grant application: Art Museum of Western Virginia, 2006 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Blue Ridge Regional Library, 2000 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Center for the History and Culture of Central Virginia, 1998 (Box 1)
- Grant application: Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Fredericksburg Museums, 2002 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Library of Virginia - WRVA Radio Sound Preservation and Conversion Project, 2002 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Library of Virginia - WRVA Radio Sound Preservation and Conversion Project, 2002-2004 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Montpelier, 2006 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Orange County Historical Society, 2003 (Box 2)
- Grant application: University of Virginia's College at Wise, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
- Grant application: University of Virginia's College at Wise, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Virginia Commonwealth University, 2003 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Virginia Home for Boys/C and O, 1997 (Box 1)
- Grant application: Virginia Museum of Transportation, 1999 (Box 1)
- Grant application: Virginia Museum of Transportation, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Virginia State University, 2006 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Virginia Tech-E. Petterson Architectural Archive, 2005 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Virginia Union University, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant application: Woodrow Wilson Library, 2007 (Box 2)
- Grant applications, 2001 May (Box 3)
- Grant applications, 2002 May (Box 3)
- Grant evaluations, 2000 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations, 2005 Dec (Box 3)
- Grant evaluations: Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations: Orange County Historical Society, 2003 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations: University of Virginia's College at Wise, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations: Virginia Commonwealth University, 2003 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations: Virginia Museum of Transportation, 2001 (Box 2)
- Grant evaluations: Woodrow Wilson Library, 2007 (Box 3)
- MARAC, Virginia Caucus meeting, 2001 Mar 30 (Box 1)
- Massachusetts SHRAB Strategic Plan and technical notes, 1999 (Box 1)
- NAADAC, 1997 July 22 (Box 1)
- NAGARA annual meeting, Columbia, SC, 2000 July 19-22 (Box 1)
- NAGARA annual meeting, 2001 (Box 1)
- National Forum on Archival Continuing Education (NFACE), 1999-2002 (Box 1)
- NHPRC letter, 2007 (Box 3)
- NHPRC Planning Grant Evaluation, 1998 (Box 1)
- Orange County Historical Society, 2004 (Box 3)
- Reports, etc., from other states, n.d. (Box 1)
- Save America's Treasures grant program - application for official project status, 1998 (Box 1)
- SHRAB administrative support grant, 2000-2004 (Box 2)
- SHRAB appointments, 2005 (Box 2)
- SHRAB Disaster Planning Grant, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- SHRAB Evaluation forms, 1996 (Box 1)
- SHRAB grant 2001-033 - Administrative support grant, 2000 Jun (Box 3)
- SHRAB-NAADAC Board Evaluations, 1997 (Box 1)
- SHRAB-NAADAC grant, 1997 (Box 2)
- SHRAB News, 2007 (Box 2)
- SHRAB surveys, 2006 (Box 2)
- South Carolina RFP for Consultant, n.d. (Box 1)
- State Historical Recrods Advisory Board, 1996 (Box 1)
- Strategic Plan, n.d. (Box 1)
- Stratecic planning, 1996 (Box 3)